ingramcontent.com 2018-10-13

# Privacy Policy Details | Ingram Content Group

We use cookies so you get the best experience on our website. By using our site, you are agreeing to our Cookie Policy.[Accept & Close]()

**JUMP TO:**   
_Privacy Policy Summary_  |  _Full Privacy Policy_  |  _Cookie Notice_

* * *

### **PRIVACY POLICY SUMMARY**

_Last Updated May 11, 2018_

By visiting and using this website to establish an account, provide us any personal information, respond to our e-mails, request additional information from us, contact customer support, purchase products or request other services or assistance from us (the “Services”), you consent to the collection, use, storage, and sharing of Your personal data as described in our full Privacy Policy which can be accessed _here_.  Capitalized terms used herein shall have the definitions given to such terms in the full Privacy Policy. 

Our Privacy Policy also includes our  _Cookies Notice_.

**IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY, DO NOT USE THIS WEBSITE**.

Ingram Content Group acts as a data controller for the personal information we process on our own behalf, and as a data processor for personal information we process based on the instructions of You or another third party who provides us personal information.

We primarily process your data from and within the United States. However, this policy will control even where We process your data outside the United States.

We collect information from you when you request any information from us or register on our website.  We will then ask you to provide basic contact information including your name, address, phone number, e-mail address, and telephone number.

**Additional information we collect from you:**

  * Your billing or other credit information when you purchase products or services, including billing address and shipping address.
  * Our website uses cookies, web beacons, and other common technologies to keep track of your interactions with the website. When we use cookies, web beacons or other common technologies, we use session cookies (that last until you close your browser) or persistent cookies (that last until you or your browser delete them).
  * Your device and networks, including location data.

For more information about how we collect information or our collection practices, please e-mail: [privacy@ingramcontent.com](mailto:privacy@ingramcontent.com?subject=Lightning%20Source%20Privacy%20Policy%20Alert).

**How we may use information collected from you:**

  * we may use information to provide you with the Services you request.
  * we may use information to provide you with additional information about our affiliated companies, and/ or partners’ services, promotions, and events.
  * we may use information to improve our website functionality and/or Services.
  * we may use information to share with third-party advertising networks to help improve the delivery of ads or content most relevant, interesting and personal to you on websites and apps.
  * we may use information to share with third party companies who provide services you request on our behalf; and customer service related help and assistance when you call in to our toll-free number, send us an e-mail, or use our chat capabilities.
  * we may use information to share with third-party web analytics services (such as Google Analytics) on our Services to collect and analyze usage information through cookies and similar tools; engage in auditing, research, or reporting; assist with fraud prevention; and provide certain features to you.
  * we may use information to provide recommendations or advertising for products and services that may be of interest to you.

  * we may use information to prevent, investigate and deal with fraud, violation of intellectual property rights and other laws, and unauthorized access or use of the website or Services or, your account.
  * we may use information as otherwise reasonable and appropriate to the legitimate business needs of our other products or services.

**Your Rights**

  * You may contact us to review, correct, update or request deletion of personal information about you at [privacy@ingramcontent.com](mailto:privacy@ingramcontent.com?subject=Lightning%20Source%20Privacy%20Policy%20Alert).
  * Where appropriate, we provide you with the ability to opt-out of receiving our marketing emails by following the “unsubscribe” instructions included in those emails. However, you will still receive transactional information regarding Services that you use as a result of being a customer.
  * You may turn off cookies in your browser.

**Retention of your Personal Information**  

We may retain your personal information for a period of time, the length of which will depend on the purpose for which we originally collected the information, the instructions of a controller when we act as a processor, and/or our requirements to comply with applicable laws. 

**Reviewing, modifying and deleting your information**

You may request to review, correct, update, or delete the personal information that you have previously provided to us through our website and/or Services.  If you have registered for an account with Ingram Content Group, you may generally update your user settings, profile, organization’s settings or event registration by logging into the applicable website or Service with your username and password.

To update your billing information or discontinue your account, please contact your account representative or the customer service team for the applicable Service. 

For other requests to review, modify or delete your personal data, please review the “How to Contact Us” section below.  Requests to access, modify, or delete your information will be addressed within a reasonable timeframe.

**How to Contact Us:**

Questions regarding this Privacy Policy or our privacy practices should be directed to [privacy@ingramcontent.com](mailto:privacy@ingramcontent.com?subject=Lightning%20Source%20Privacy%20Policy%20Alert) or by mail:

Ingram Content Group

Attn: Legal Department/ Privacy

1 Ingram Blvd.

LaVergne, TN. 37086

* * *

### **FULL PRIVACY POLICY**

_Last Updated May 11, 2018_

We are committed to protecting the privacy of individuals who visit this website and/ or individuals who register to use or request our Services.  This Privacy Policy describes our privacy practices in relation to the use of our websites and the related applications, services, and programs offered by Us (collectively, the “Services”), and in relation to individuals’ choices regarding use, access and correction of personal information.  “You” means the person who accesses and uses this website, and includes the legal entity You represent in using this website on their behalf or as part of your employment.

Any reference to “We” or “Us” includes, as applicable, the Ingram Content Group entity now in existence or hereafter created or acquired who provides You the Service or information from within a website that includes a link to this Privacy Policy.  Ingram Content Group may include, without limitation, Ingram Content Group LLC, Ingram Book Group LLC, Ingram Fulfillment Services LLC, Ingram Publisher Services LLC, Book Network Int’l Limited, Ingram Library Services LLC, Tennessee Book Company LLC, Lightning Source LLC, Lightning Source UK Ltd., Lightning Source Australia Pty Limited.

The name, address, e-mail, and any payment information provided by You to us, together with information regarding the manner of use via this website, will be processed by Us, and other third-party service providers as permitted by this Privacy Policy or as otherwise permitted by law or regulation.

By using this website, You agree that We may share with third parties Aggregate Information, individual information, and locator information gathered by this website in the course of your use of the website. "Aggregate Information" is information which describes the habits, usage patterns, and/or demographics of users as a group, but does not describe or reveal the actual identity of any particular user.

**Transfer of your personal information from the EEA**

Given that the internet is a global environment, using the internet to collect and process personal information involves the transmission of data on an international basis. The use of this website resulting in the transfer of personal information from the European Economic Area (EEA) or Switzerland to non-EEA countries is in accordance with this Privacy Policy and your continued use of our Services.  Therefore, by using this website or any Service, You agree to the transfer, storage or use of your personal information outside your country of residence to any country (including without limitation the United States, Canada, the United Kingdom, or Australia) where We have facilities or We engage third parties (such as payment processors, cloud service providers, or other IT providers and other companies that provide services as We request). You understand that the countries to which We may transfer personal information may not have as comprehensive data protection requirements as does your country.

Where Australia’s Privacy Act applies to your personal information, You agree that we will not be responsible for a third-party’s breach or mishandling of your personal information, and You agree not to seek redress from us.

**Disclosure of Personal Information**

We disclose your personal information to third parties who provide some of our Services through contractual arrangements or where sharing of personal information is necessary to operate our website, and to our affiliated companies to share their services with You.

For example, We:

  * provide your credit card information to the card-issuing bank to confirm payment for products and services purchased on our websites.
  * provide your shipping address to the delivery service to deliver products that You ordered.

  * share your personal information with third parties performing certain tasks on our behalf, which may include operational or administrative assistance of the website or Services.

  * share your personal information with third party companies who provide customer service related help and assistance when You call in to our toll-free number, send Us an e-mail, or use our chat capabilities, limited to that personal information reasonably required to resolve the purpose for which You contacted Us.

  * use your information to conduct polls or surveys.

We may also share personal information as otherwise described to You at the point of collection.

**Where Required or Permitted By law**

We may disclose personal information (i) if it is required by law enforcement or judicial authorities; (ii) if We have a good faith belief that We are required or permitted to do so by law or legal process; or (iii) to protect the rights, reputation, property or safety of Ingram Content Group.

**Marketing**  
We may provide additional information to You via e-mail, including service messages with important information about your account, informative newsletters, special promotions, and other announcements related to the products and Services We offer.  You will have the option to manage your subscriptions to these communications or unsubscribe from receiving e-mail messages. 

We may share your personal information with third-party advertisers or advertising networks for their advertising, such as Facebook.  For example, if You click on an ad, the ad poster will know You visited the page that You clicked on. Also, advertising partners can associate personal data collected by the advertiser directly from You with our cookies and similar technologies. Click [_here_](https://www.facebook.com/help/146952742043748?helpref=related) to learn how to block ads or opt out of ads on Facebook.

**Children's Privacy**

You must be 18 years of age or older to create an account on this website.  We do not knowingly solicit orders or collect personal information from children under the age of 18.  If You have reason to believe that any personal information has been submitted to Us by a child under thirteen, contact Us and upon verification of each claim, We will delete that personal information as soon as possible.  

**Your Device and Location**

When You visit or leave this website (including our plugins or cookies or similar technology on third-party websites), We receive the URL of both the website You came from and the one You go to next. We may also gather information about your IP address, proxy server, operating system, web browser and add-ons, device identifier and features, and/or ISP or your mobile carrier.

If You use our Services from a mobile device, that device will send Us data about your location. Most devices allow You to prevent location data from being sent to Us.

**Cookies**  
This website employs "cookies" to speed navigation of the website, recognize each user and the user’s access privileges, and track a user's website usage.  Please view our Cookies Notice for more information regarding our use of cookies.

**Links to Other Sites**

This website may contain links to other websites. Please be aware that We are not responsible for the privacy policies and/or practices of such other websites. We encourage You to read the privacy statements of any linked sites as their privacy practices may differ from ours.

**Security**

We take information security seriously and have taken various measures to keep your personal information secure from unauthorized access or disclosure, whether stored physically or electronically. We work to protect the security of your personal information during transmission by using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, which encrypts personal information You provide Us. We have established administrative, technical, physical, electronic and managerial procedures to help prevent unauthorized access, and use the personal information collected from You in accordance with this Privacy Policy. However, **Ingram Content Group cannot guarantee complete security, as it does not exist on the internet.**   It is important for You to also protect yourself against unauthorized access to your password and to your device.

**Your Rights and Choices**

Where applicable laws provide, You may have certain rights with respect to your personal information as further described in this section.  If You would like further information regarding your data subject rights, or You would like to exercise any of these rights, please contact Us as described in the “How to Contact Us” section at the end of this Privacy Policy.

You can tell Us to not contact You with promotional information regarding our Services and those of third parties either at the point information is requested on our website (by checking or un-ticking, as directed, the relevant box) or by following the “unsubscribe” instructions on promotional communications sent to You.

**_Where applicable, You may request that We:_**

  * provide access to and/or a copy of certain personal information we hold about You.
  * prevent the processing of your personal information for direct-marketing purposes (including any direct marketing processing based on profiling).
  * update your personal information which is out of date or incorrect.
  * (where reasonable), restrict the way that We process and disclose certain of your personal information.
  * Provide You your personal information.
  * cease processing of your personal information.
  * delete certain information which We are holding about You (request that you be forgotten).

In some circumstances, for example if We need to continue processing Your personal information for our legitimate interests or to comply with a legal obligation, we may not be able to grant your requests.  An exercise of the right to be forgotten will result in your inability to use the website and/or Service, and will break any linkage between your prior account and your historical engagement data.

Requests & Responses:

  * We may request You provide Us with information necessary to confirm your identity before responding to your request. In the case of access and correction requests, please provide as much detail as You can about the particular personal data You seek, in order to help us locate it.
  * We will consider all requests and provide our response within the time period stated by applicable law.
  * Where We decide not to make a requested correction to your personal data and You disagree, You may ask us to make a note of your requested correction with the personal information we hold.
  * In situations where We process your personal information only on behalf of a customer such as a publisher, We will refer your request to the relevant party and cooperate with their handling of the request.

**CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS:** California law permits visitors who are California residents to request once per year certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for such third parties’ direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an email to privacy@ingramcontent.com or write to us at Ingram Content Group, Attn: Legal Department/Privacy, One Ingram Blvd., LaVergne, TN., 37086.

**Change of Control or Sale**

We may share your personal information in the event our business or Service is sold, as part of a merger or change in control, or in preparation for these events. Any successor entity will have the right to continue to use your personal information.

**Updates to This Policy**

If Ingram Content Group changes or updates this Privacy Policy, We will post those changes and updates on this page so You are always aware of what personal information We collect, how We use your personal information, and under what circumstances We disclose it to third parties. Ingram Content Group encourages You to review this Privacy Policy from time to time so You will know if the Privacy Policy has been updated or amended.

**How to Contact Us:**

Questions regarding Ingram Content Group’s Privacy Policy should be directed to [_privacy@ingramcontent.com_](mailto:privacy@ingramcontent.com?subject=Lightning%20Source%20Privacy%20Policy%20Alert):

Or, If You have any _legal_ questions related to this Privacy Policy, We can be reached at [_legal@ingramcontent.com_](mailto:legal@ingramcontent.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy) or by mail to the address below:

Ingram Content Group

Attn: Legal Department

One Ingram Blvd.

LaVergne, TN. 37086

* * *

### **INGRAM CONTENT GROUP COOKIES NOTICE**

_Last Updated May 11, 2018_

We use and allow certain other companies to use certain tracking technologies including cookies, web beacons, and other similar technologies on our website to provide You information and/ or services, including, without limitation,  [www.ingramcontent.com](http://www.ingramcontent.com/) and [_www.ingramspark.com_](http://www.ingramspark.com/); any of our owned web retail stores; other products controlled, owned or licensed by Us; and any other products or services that include a link to this Cookie Notice (collectively, the “Products”).

Any reference to “We” or “Us” includes, as applicable, the Ingram Content Group entity now in existence or hereafter created or acquired who provides You the Service or information from within a website that includes a link to the Privacy Policy.  Ingram Content Group may include, without limitation, Ingram Content Group LLC, Ingram Book Group LLC, Ingram Fulfillment Services LLC, Ingram Publisher Services LLC, Book Network Int’l Limited, Ingram Library Services LLC, Tennessee Book Company LLC, Lightning Source LLC, Lightning Source UK Ltd., Lightning Source Australia Pty Limited.

This Cookie Notice explains what Cookies are, why We use them, and your rights to control our use of them.  It is a part of, and should be read in conjunction with, our Privacy Policy.

Please read our _Privacy Policy_ for more information about our privacy practices.

**What are Cookies?**

Cookies are text files that contain information and are downloaded to your computer or mobile device when You visit a website. They are useful because they allow websites to recognize a user's device. They are then returned to the original website on each subsequent visit or to any other website that recognizes them. For more information about cookies, You can visit [_www.allaboutcookies.org_](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

The term "Cookies" is used in this Cookie Policy to include all similar techniques and technology, including web beacons and log files.  A web beacon is a small graphic image or other web programming code (also known as “clear GIFs” or “pixel tags”) that may be included in our web pages and messages.

**Types of Information We Collect**

Cookies help Us learn how our Products are used and to improve the Products. Examples of the types of information that We collect through Cookies include:

  * The number of website visitors and website views, the pages of Products viewed, the clicks made on the Products, and the total duration of navigation on the Products;
  * The name of the page that referred You to our website;
  * Whether this is your first time visiting our website;
  * Your viewing preferences (e.g. layout, sizing preferences, language etc.);
  * Your city and country; and
  * the type of browser used and your IP address, so that We can identify You during your future visits.

**How We Use Cookies**

Examples of ways We use Cookies include:

  * To track usage of the Products;
  * To control the display of ads, including interest-based ads;
  * To determine if You opened our emails;
  * To customize elements of the promotional layout and/or content of the pages of our website; and
  * To personalize information.

We (or third-party service providers on our behalf) may also use Cookies to collect aggregate information about Products on an anonymous basis. We may share such anonymous information with our business partners, advertisers and other third parties for any business purpose.

**Types of Cookies We Use on Our Products**

We use first party and third-party Cookies for several reasons. Some Cookies are required for technical reasons in order for our Products to operate, and We refer to these as "essential" or "strictly necessary" Cookies. Other Cookies enable Us to track and target the interests of our users and to enhance the experience on our Products. Third parties also serve Cookies through our Products for advertising, analytics and other purposes. The specific types of first and third-party Cookies served through our Products and the functions they perform are described in more detail below.

**First-party Cookies**

These Cookies are created by ICG. They allow You to browse our Products and use their features.

_Essential Cookies:_ These Cookies are strictly necessary to allow You to move around the Products and use their features. Without these Cookies, We cannot enable the Products to function on your device. Therefore, these Cookies cannot be disabled.

_Functional Cookies_ : These Cookies allow us to remember choices You make on our Products (such as your preferred language or the region You are in). To refuse these Cookies, please follow the instructions below under the section Cookie Management. Note that by disabling functional Cookies, You may not be able to use some of our features or those features may not function properly.

_Embedded Scripts._ An embedded script is programming code that is designed to collect information about your interactions with the Products, such as the links You click on. The code is temporarily downloaded onto your computer or other device, is active only while You are connected to the Products, and is deactivated or deleted thereafter.

_Analytics Cookies_ : We use Cookies and other identifiers to see how You use our Products in order to enhance their performance and develop them according to the preferences of our customers and visitors. For example, Cookies may be used to maintain a consistency across our Products, determine how visitors use our Products, track errors, and measure the effectiveness of our promotional campaigns. To refuse these Cookies, see the section Cookie Management.

**Third-Party Cookies**

Some of our third-party partners (including advertisers and marketing services companies) may set and access Cookies on your device as well, or We may do so on their behalf. We do not have control over how these third parties use such Cookies or the information derived therefrom, and this Privacy Policy does not cover any use of information that such third parties may collect from You or the methods used by the third parties to collect that information. These types of Cookies include:

_Advertising Cookies_ : These Cookies, defined exclusively by third parties, collect several types of data about your browsing habits, as well as your preferences for products and services. This information allows Us to serve You relevant advertisements on our Products. To refuse these Cookies, please follow the instructions below under the section Cookie Management. Some advertisements may also contain an icon that You may click on to find out more about how to manage your advertising preferences.

_Third-Party Functional Cookies_ : These Cookies are defined by third parties who support our Products and allow You to use useful services and features. To refuse these Cookies, please follow the instructions below under the section Cookie Management.

**Duration of storage of Cookies on your device**

We use both “session Cookies” (which expire once You close your web browser) and “persistent Cookies” (which stay on your computer until You delete them).

**Cookie Management**

_Analytics_

To learn about Google Analytics’ currently available opt-outs for the Web, please visit [_https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/181881?hl=en_](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/181881?hl=en).

_Disabling Advertising Cookies_

Some advertising service providers may be members of the Network Advertising Initiative, which offers a single location to opt out of ad targeting from member companies. If You opt-out of receiving targeted ads in this manner, You will continue to receive advertising messages after You opt-out, but they will not be tailored based on your usage of the Products or third-party websites. If You would like to learn information about how advertisers’ use of tracking technologies and your options, visit [_http://www.networkadvertising.org_](http://www.networkadvertising.org/). To learn more about how interest-based information is collected, whether the companies we use are part of an industry network regarding behavioral advertising and to know your choices, visit [_http://www.aboutads.info_](http://www.aboutads.info/). The collection of information via certain ads served to users in Canada may be managed by visiting [_youradchoices.ca_](http://www.youradchoices.ca/).

Keep in mind an opt-out is Cookie-based and only affects the specific device and browser on which the opt-out is applied.

_Using Browser Settings_

You can disable and/or delete most types of Cookies through your browser settings. If You use your browser settings to block all Cookies, You may not be able to access parts of our or others’ Products. For information about how to modify the Cookies settings on some popular browsers please see the following:

Apple Safari [_http://support.apple.com/kb/PH5042_](http://support.apple.com/kb/PH5042)

Google Chrome [_https://support.google.com/chrome/bin/answer.py?hl=en &answer=95647&p=cpn_cookies_](https://support.google.com/chrome/bin/answer.py?hl=en&answer=95647&p=cpn_cookies)

Microsoft Internet Explorer http://windows.microsoft.com/en-US/windows7/How-to-manage-cookies-in-Internet-Explorer-9 or [_https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies_](https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies)

Mozilla Firefox [_http://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/Cookies_](http://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/Cookies)

**Changes to the Cookies Notice**

We may revise this Notice from time to time. Changes made will be reflected on this page. Please re-visit this Cookie Notice regularly to stay informed about our use of Cookies. If You have any questions, please contact Us as set forth below.

**Contact Us**

If You have questions about the use of Cookies on our Products, please contact [_privacy@ingramcontent.com_](mailto:privacy@ingramcontent.com).
